### Sandeep Subbiah Selvakumar (1) Featured



Senior Programmer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Coding, Web Development, Requirement Gathering, Software Testing, Application Support, Hibernate, Core Java, Spring, Struts, J2Ee, Maven, JBoss, Web Services, SQL, Portal



Current Designation: Senior Programmer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Current Company: Kumaran Systems Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Chennai Highest Degree:

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Programmer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Coding, Web

Development, Requirement Gathering, Software Testing, Application Support, Hibernate, Core

Java, Spring, Struts, J2Ee, Maven, JBoss, Web Services, SQL, Portal

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

### Summary

Passionate full stack developer with 4+ years which includes exposure on discrete global projects in mobile and web applications.

Posses hands on experience on enterprise based, business oriented and custom application with adoptable and interactive interface

# **Work Experience**

Kumaran Systems as Senior Programmer

Dec 2019 to Oct 2020

**Kumaran Systems** as Senior Programmer

Dec 2019 to Till Date

Migration of existing project to latest technology. Analyzing actual project and customizing as per the specification. Implementation on Restful Web Services and Back-end.

Deployment & Patch generation on scrum.

Optimizing for performance based on insights.

Karya Technologies as Associate Programmer Analyst

Apr 2017 to Nov 2019

Acquiring the concept, requirement and analyze to initiate the development.

Pro-actively provided suggestions for application to target platforms, limitations and scalability.

Design the user interface and implementing business logic with standard functional

requirements, code integration and testing the functionalities iteratively.

Maintaining the application by fixing functional failures, operational updates, upgrading

platform and enhancing features.

Deployment initiates the resource to be available for the end user which indeed needs guidance

documentation for intended usage.

Monitoring and up-scaling the application based on the insights

#### Wahrheit Infotech as Software Trainee

May 2016 to Apr 2017

Actively participated with client for requirements analysis, architecture and produce software design.

Composed scalable code by managing and prioritizing task in Java.

Revise, update, refactor, test, debug code and deploy applications.

Develop documentation throughout the software development life cycle (SDLC)

Managed applications and provided bug fixes, enhancements and continuous improvement in line with customer requirements.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from MAAMALLAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, ANNA UNIVERSITY in 2015

PG: in 0

#### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Angular			
CORE JAVA			
Hibernate			
Mongo DB, Sql			
springboot			
MAVEN/Gradle			
JBoss			

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Tamil	Expert			
Telugu	Proficient			

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

**Employment Status: Full time**